                                                                      ::1111::1111
                                                                      H MM■11 ■
                                                                      IXOIXO
                                                                      EISTME1882

WEEKEND SNACK: FUNCTIONS
1. isEven(integer) -> boolean: Write a function that takes an integer and returns true if the 
integer is even and returns false if the integer is odd.
2. isPrimeNumber(integer)-> boolean: Write a function that takes an integer and returns 
true if the number is a prime number and returns false if it is not a prime number.
3. subtract(integer, integer)-> integer: Write a function that takes 2 integers and returns the 
positive difference irrespective of the parameter order. ie 3, 7 and 7, 3 should return 4.
4. divide(integer, integer)-> float: Write a function that takes 2 integers and returns the 
quotient. If the second integer is 0 (zero). please return 0 as your quotient.
5. factor0f(integer)-> integer: Write a function that takes an integer and returns the number 
of factor for the integer. ie, if the function takes in 10, it should return 4 because factors of 10 
are 1,2,5,10.
6. isSquare(integer)->boolean: Write a function that takes an integer and returns true if the 
integer is a square number. ie if I pass in 25, the function should return true.
7. isPalindrome(integer)->boolean: Write a function that takes an 5 digit integer and returns 
true if it is a palindrome. ie if I pass in 54145, it should return true.
8. factorialOf(integer)-> long: Write a function that takes an integer and returns the 
factorial of the number. If I pass in 5, i expect 120 (5 * 4 * 3 * 2 *1).
9. square0f(integer) -> long: Write a function that takes an integer and returns the square 
of the number. if I pass in 5, i expect 25(5 * 5).
You can google the mathematics terms used in this assignment to gain clarity before doing 
the tasks.
Create a class called Kata and create all of the functions in the class.
Submission instruction: push the code alongside your existing code to github and add me 
as a contributor (my handle is i-am-chibuzo).
PS: This snack is not a group snack, DO NOT SHARE. 
Enjoy your short weekend






Website: www.semicolon.africa Tel: 0906 000 8609
Email: info@semicolon.africa  Social: @semicolonafrica                 0 semicolon

